## Reito Serizawa

Jersey City, NJ | (979) 661-4280 | s.reitiger@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

## **Software Engineer**

Bilingual software engineer, experienced in full-stack web development, object-oriented programming, and test-driven development. Superb problem-solving and data management skills sharpened by analyzing data sets and tackling application issues. Exceptional collaborative skills honed in agile software development. Possesses a passion for new technologies.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript, Ruby, Python, React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, Django, SQL, PostgreSQL, Git, Heroku, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, REST APIs

## **Technical Projects**

#### **Zoomies** - GitHub | Demo

A dog park application to create a profile of pet dogs, check in and out at dog parks and see active dogs at each park with profiles.

- Built the full-stack application with React and Ruby on Rails following the MVC pattern.
- Implemented features to check in and out, and view active dogs at each park by managing relational databases.
- Handled unauthorized access protection and auto-login persistence by using bcrypt's hashing and salting, and sessions.

## StudyBuddy - GitHub | Demo

A chat application to create a profile and a chat room to study programming with others, and send and delete messages.

- Built the full-stack application with Django following the MVT architecture.
- Created a custom user model to customize user profile information by the Django authentication system.
- Designed a REST API with CRUD operations to connect with the client side by Django REST framework.

# Tippie - GitHub | Demo

A reviewing application for restaurants and servers that allows users to tip based on the service provided by each server.

- Built the full-stack application with a REST API to improve data handling by converting Yelp API through REST Client.
- Integrated ActiveRecord validations in Ruby on Rails to monitor reviews to avoid online insults.
- Leveraged the knowledge with serializers and connected each relational database to access and use data from the front end.

## **Work Experience**

**Blued Japan** 

Marketing Business Development Manager

Tokyo, Japan May 2020-October 2021

- Initiated business development and marketing activities by leading software development and marketing teams.
- Built relationships with 6 nonprofit organizations (NPO), 3 corporations, and 500+ lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) related facilities, and executed collaborations through educational activities, co-produced products, and events.
- Pitched online advertisement plans focusing on segregated areas of Japan and signboard plans in Tokyo and Osaka, and managed each advertisement accordingly.

eBay

Tokyo, Japan

Associate Sales Manager, Direct Sales, Business Development

June 2019-May 2020

- Generated sales leads and acquired large merchants for cross-border trade opportunities through meetings, calls, and seminars.
- Assessed the clients' needs and advised effective selling and marketing plans in addition to installing third-party tools to reduce workforce and cost.
- Developed partnerships with e-commerce software vendors and collaborated with their services to improve client revenue.

#### **AlphaSights**

Associate, Strategic Consulting Division

Tokyo, Japan; Hong Kong, Hong Kong March 2018-April 2019

- Managed client relationships by regularly communicating throughout the projects and successfully grew existing accounts by "in-account user growth."
- Was responsible for 35+ projects across Consumer Goods (30%), Healthcare (20%), and Financial Services (16%) as a project lead and in cooperation with global offices.
- Contributed to the generation of \(\frac{\pma}{2}\),000,000 monthly in profits, on average, on projects across global markets.

#### Education

**Flatiron School** 

Full-stack Software Engineering Bootcamp

New York, USA April 2022-July 2022

**Senshu University** 

Bachelor of Arts (B.A) in English Literature

Kanagawa, Japan April 2014-March 2018

**University of Oregon** 

Oregon, USA June 2016-March 2017

Exchange program in English and Entrepreneurship